[
    {
        "question": "Central African Republic gaines its independence from which European country in 1960?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Great Lakes are there?",
        "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is home to Colman`s mustard?",
        "answer": "Norwich"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alba is the Gaelic name for what country?",
        "answer": "Scotland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of El Salvador?",
        "answer": "San Salvador"
    },
    {
        "question": "What body of water separates Alaska from Russia?",
        "answer": "Bering Strait"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Bering Strait separates Russia from which US state?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Hanover, New Hampshire?",
        "answer": "Darthmouth College"
    },
    {
        "question": "The US city of Mobile sites on the shores of what bay?",
        "answer": "Mobile Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is serviced by the Hartsfield International Airport?",
        "answer": "Atlanta"
    },
    {
        "question": "Liberty Island is located in the harbor of what US city?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "Central African Republic shares its northern border with mostly which country?",
        "answer": "Chad"
    },
    {
        "question": "Central African Republic shares its western border with which country?",
        "answer": "Cameroon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the west?",
        "answer": "Cameroon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the east?",
        "answer": "South Sudan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Central African Republic shares its eastern border with which country?",
        "answer": "South Sudan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the state bird of Mississippi?",
        "answer": "Northern Mockingbird"
    },
    {
        "question": "Until 1820, Maine was part of which US state?",
        "answer": "Massachusetts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does Machu Picchu translate to in English?",
        "answer": "Old mountain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Knoxville, Tennessee sits on the bank of what river?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "question": "Miami, Florida sits on the bank of what bay?",
        "answer": "Biscayne Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Lynchburg, Tennessee famous for?",
        "answer": "Jack Daniels whiskey"
    },
    {
        "question": "The `Atomium` landmark is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country is the grave of the famous German philosopher Immanuel Kant located?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Rabbit Ears Range, Castle Peak, and Mt. Massive are all in what US State",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "The City of Hot Coffee is in what US state?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city known as Hot Coffee is located in what US state?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "question": "The counties of Washington, Monroe, Franklin, Polk, Jefferson, Jackson, and Liberty are in what US state?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the lowest freshwater lake, by altitude, in the world?",
        "answer": "Lake Tiberias"
    },
    {
        "question": "What geographical boundary was first surveyed in 1763 by Charles Mason and Jeremiah Dixon?",
        "answer": "The Mason-Dixon Line"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to a `singing beach`?",
        "answer": "Massachusetts"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prime meridian passes through which major U.K. city?",
        "answer": "London - The prime meridian, the imaginary line dividing the eastern and western hemispheres, passes through London`s Greenwich Observatory."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the newest country in Europe?",
        "answer": "Kosovo -- In 2008, the country declared its independence from Serbia; in 2010, Kosovo`s sovereignty was formally recognized by the International Court of Justice."
    },
    {
        "question": "What bird and its chicks are featured on Louisiana`s state flag?",
        "answer": "Pelican -- The flag also features three drops of the mother`s blood, symbolizing Louisiana`s intention to sacrifice everything for its citizens."
    },
    {
        "question": "What group of countries are often referred to as Great Britain?",
        "answer": "England, Scotland, and Wales"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as `The Hub of the Universe`?",
        "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only Romance language spoken in Eastern Europe?",
        "answer": "Romanian"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the tallest peak in Colorado?",
        "answer": "Mt. Elbert"
    },
    {
        "question": "`Eureka!` is the official motto of which US state?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two U.S. national parks are located within the Arctic Circle?",
        "answer": "Gates of the Arctic National Park and Kobuk Valley National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the longest river in Australia?",
        "answer": "Murray River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four largest islands in Canada?",
        "answer": "Baffin, Victoria, Ellesmere and Newfoundland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river forms part of the border between England & Scotland?",
        "answer": "River Tweed"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longest river solely in England?",
        "answer": "The Thames"
    },
    {
        "question": "Into which sea does the Volga river flow?",
        "answer": "The Caspian Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which river is the Kariba Dam?",
        "answer": "The Zambezi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosts the world`s largest Passover Seder every year?",
        "answer": "Kathmandu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country does Denmark share its only land border with?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country did the Mambo dance originate?",
        "answer": "Cuba"
    }
]